Prints and Printing Lantern Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Prints and Printing Lantern Slide Collection
1900-1960
VRC 2300
Yale University Arts Library
15.3
46 boxes
Collection consists of black and white glass lantern slides of prints and printing techniques worldwide.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of black and white glass lantern slides of prints and printing techniques worldwide.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by geographical region or country. Further arranged by individual artist name. Individual artist name sections may be preceded by an Anonymous or Miscellaneous grouping. Preliminary section on printing techniques (lettering and printed books).
Prints; Printing; Lantern slides; Slides; Reproductions
- Prints (Box 1)
  - General Processes (Box 1)
    - Printing in relief (Box 1)
      - Relief printing (Box 1)
        - Chiaroscuro (Box 1)
        - Woodcuts (Box 1)
        - Wood engraving (Box 1)
    - Intaglio Prints (Box 1)
      - Intaglio Principles (Box 1)
      - Intaglio Printing (Box 1)
      - Comparison—etching and engraving (Box 1)
      - Drypoint (Box 1)
      - Engraving (Box 1)
      - Etching (Box 1)
      - Aquatint (Box 1)
      - Stipple (Box 1)
      - Crayon Manner (Box 1)
      - Mezzo Tint (Box 1)
    - Surfable Prints (Box 1)
  - China (Box 1)
    - General (Box 1)
  - Japan (Box 1)
    - Artist Unknown (Box 1)
      - Nagasaki color prints (Box 1)
    - Artist A-Z (Box 1)
      - Boncho, Ippitsusai, ac. 1767-1775 (Box 1)
      - Harunobu, Suzuki, 1725-1770 (Box 2)
      - Hiroshige, Utagawa, 1797-1858 (Box 2)
      - Hokusai, Katsushika, 1760-1849 (Box 2)
      - Kiyomasu, Torii, 1702-1963 (Box 2)
      - Kiyomitsu, Torii, 1735-1785 (Box 2)
      - Kiyonaga, Torii, 1752-1815 (Box 2)
      - Kiyonobu, Torii, 1667-4-1729 (Box 2)
      - Koriusai, Isoda, active c. 1760-1780 (Box 2)
      - Kunisada, 1786-1865 (Box 2)
      - Kuniyoshi, Utagawa, 1798-1861 (Box 2)
      - Masanobu, Okumura, c.1685-1768 (Box 2)
      - Moronobu, Hishikawa, 1625-1695 (Box 2)
      - Sharaku, Toshusai, active, 1794-1795 (Box 2)
      - Shin-Sei (Box 2)
      - Shunman, Kobo, 1757-1820 (Box 2)
      - Shunsho, Katsukawa, 1726-1793 (Box 2)
      - Toyokuni, Utagawa, 1769-1825 (Box 3)
      - Toynobu, Ishikawa, 1711-1785 (Box 3)
      - Utamoro, Kitagawa, 1753-1806 (Box 3)
  - Austria (Box 3)
  - Belgium (Box 3)
    - Artists (Box 3)
      - Doudelet, Charles (Box 3)
      - Ensor, James, 160-1949 (Box 3)
  - Britain (Box 3)
    - 16th century (Box 3)
    - 17th century (Box 3)
    - 18th century (Box 3)
    - 19th century (Box 3–4)
    - 20th century (Box 4)
    - Illustrations to Alice in Wonderland (Box 4)
    - Anderson, Stanley (Box 4)
    - Austin, Robert (Box 4)
    - Beardsley, Aubrey, 1872-1898 (Box 4)
    - Bewick, Thomas, 1753-1828 (Box 4)
    - Blake, Peter, 1920- (Box 4)
    - Blake, William, 1757-1827 (Box 4)
      - America (Box 4)
      - Book of Job (Box 4)
      - Book of Thel (Box 4)
      - Gates of Paradise (Box 4)
      - Pastoral of Vigil (Box 4)
      - Songs of Experience (Box 4)
      - Songs of Innocence (Box 4)
    - Bone, Muirhead (Box 4)
    - Bonington, Richard, 1801-1828 (Box 5)
    - Brockhurst, Gerald (Box 5)
    - Brown, Ford Maddox, 1821-1893 (Box 5)
    - Burne-Jones, Edward, 1833-1898 (Box 5)
    - Catherwood, Frederick, 1799-1854 (Box 5)
    - Caxton, William (Box 5)
    - Clavert, Edward, 1799-1883 (Box 5)
    - Cockson, Thomas (Box 5)
    - Constable, John, 1776-1837 (Box 5)
    - Corbould, Edward, 1815-1905 (Box 5)
    - Cotman, John, 1782-1842 (Box 5)
    - Craig, Gordon (Box 5)
    - Crane, Walter, 1845-1915 (Box 5)
    - Cruikshank, George, 1792-1878 (Box 5)
    - Dalziel, Edward (Box 5)
    - Dawe, Philip (Box 5)
    - Daniell, Thomas, 1749-1840 (Box 5)
    - Doyle, Richard, 1824-1883 (Box 5)
    - Daniell, William, 1769-1837 (Box 5)
    - Earlom, Richard, 1743-1822 (Box 5)
    - Egerton, Daniel T., ac.1824-1842 (Box 5)
    - Faber, Jean, c.1695-1756 (Box 5)
    - Faber, Johan, 1660-1721 (Box 5)
    - Faithorne, William (Box 5)
    - Fibles, Samuel Luke, 1844-1927 (Box 5)
    - Fisher, Edward, 1730-1785 (Box 5)
    - Flaxman, John, 1755-1826 (Box 6)
    - Gainsborough, Thomas, 1727-1788 (Box 6)
    - Gillray, James, 1757-1815 (Box 6)
    - Girtin, Thomas, 1775-1802 (Box 6)
    - Green, Charles, 1840-1898 (Box 6)
    - Green, Valentin, 1739-1813 (Box 6)
    - Griggs, F.L., 1876- (Box 6)
    - Havell, Robert and Daniel (Box 6)
    - Hayden, Francis Seymour, 1818-1910 (Box 6)
    - Hogarth, William, 1697-1764 (Box 6)
      - Beer Street (Box 6)
      - Credulity, Superstition & Fanaticism (Box 6)
      - Gin Lane (Box 6)
      - A Harlot's Progress (Box 7)
      - Marriage a la Mode (Box 7)
      - The Rake's Progress (Box 7)
    - Hunt, William Holman, 1827-1910 (Box 7)
    - Jackson, John B. (Box 7)
    - John, Augustus (Box 7)
    - Keene, Charles (Box 7)
    - Lawless, Matthes J., 1837-1864 (Box 7)
    - Leech, John, 1817-1864 (Box 7)
    - Mackmurdo, Arthur, 1851-1942 (Box 7)
    - Millais, Sir John E., 1829-1896 (Box 7)
    - Morris, William, 1834-1896 (Box 7)
      - Kelmscott Chaucer (Box 7)
    - Nixon, John, 1760-1818 (Box 7)
    - Pinwell, George J., 1842-1875 (Box 7)
    - Poynter, E.H., 1836-1919 (Box 7)
    - Prout, Samuel, 1783-1852 (Box 7)
    - Pugin, A. Welby (Box 7)
    - Reynolds, Joshua (after) (Box 7)
    - Rowlandson, Thomas, 1756-1827 (Box 7)
    - Rossetti, Dante (Box 7)
    - Sandys, Fred, 1832-1904 (Box 8)
    - Searle, Ronald (Box 8)
    - Small, William (Box 8)
    - Spooner, Charles (Box 8)
    - Sutherland, Graham, 1903-1980 (Box 8)
    - Tenniel, John, 1820-1914 (Box 8)
    - Thackeray, Wm. M., 1811-1863 (Box 8)
    - Turner, Joseph Mallord William, 1775-1851 (Box 8)
    - Walker, Frederick, 1840-1875 (Box 8)
    - Watson, John D., 1832-1892 (Box 8)
    - Watson, Thomas (Box 8)
    - Wedgewood, Geoffrey (Box 8)
    - Westall, Richard, 1765-1836 (Box 8)
    - Woodward, George, 1760-1809 (Box 8)
    - Wheatley, Francis (after) (Box 8)
  - Flanders (Box 8)
    - Artist Unknown (Box 8)
      - Vesalius, Andreas (Box 8)
        - Vesalius, Anatomy De Human Corporis Fabrica (Box 8)
      - Brueghel, Pieter, Elder, 1525-1569 (Box 8–9)
      - Bry, Theodore de, 1528-1598 (Box 9)
      - Crabbe, Frans, ac.1501-1552 (Box 9)
      - De Vos, Martin (Box 9)
      - Galle, Theodor, 1571-1633 (Box 9)
      - Huys, Frans, fl.1550-1570 (Box 9)
        General
        Xx Peter Breughel the Elder
      - Jegher, Christoph (Box 9)
      - Plantin, Christopher Antwerp (Box 9)
      - Rubens, Peter Paul, 1577-1640 (Box 9)
      - Straet, Jon von der (Box 9)
      - Sadeler, Jan, 1550-1600 (Box 9)
      - Van Dyck, Anthony, 1599-1641 (Box 9)
      - Vellert, Dirk J., ac.1511-1544 (Box 9)
      - Wierix, Jan, 1549-1615 (Box 9)
  - France (Box 9)
    - 14th Century (Box 9)
    - 15th Century (Box 10)
    - 16th Century (Box 10)
    - 17th Century (Box 10)
    - 18th Century (Box 10)
      - Diderot, Denis –Encyclopedie..., 1751-1765 (Box 10)
      - A trip to Rome (Box 10)
    - 19th Century (Box 10)
      - General (Box 11)
      - Illustrations for Chateaubriand, Genie du Christianisme (Box 11)
    - 20th Century (Box 11)
      - Bellange, Jacques, ac.1602-1617 (Box 11)
      - Berain, Jean (Box 11)
      - Blanche, Jacques Emile, 1861-1942 (Box 11)
      - Boaistuau, P. (Box 11)
      - Bonnard, Pierre, 1867-1947 (Box 11)
      - Bonnet, Louis-Maris, 1736-1793 (Box 11)
      - Bosse, Abraham de, 1602-1676 (Box 11)
      - Boucher, Francois (Box 11)
      - Bourdon, Pierre (Box 11)
      - Bouchardon, Edme, 1678-1762 (Box 11)
      - Bracquemond, Felix, 1883-1914 (Box 11)
      - Braque, Georges, 1882-1962 (Box 11)
      - Brebiette, Pierre, 1598-1650 (Box 11)
      - Bresdin, Rudolphe, 1822-1885 (Box 11)
      - Callot, Jacques, 1592-1635 (Box 11–12)
      - Cezanne, Paul, 1839-1906 (Box 12)
      - Charlet (Box 12)
      - Claude, Gallee (le Lorrain), 1600-1682 (Box 12)
      - Cochin, Charles Nicolas (elder) (Box 12)
      - Cochin, Charles Nicolas., the younger, 1715-1790 (Box 12)
      - Colibert, Nicholas (Box 12)
      - Corot, Jean B.C., 1796-1875 (Box 12)
      - Cross, Henri E., 1856-1916 (Box 12)
      - Cuvillies, Francois, 1695-1768 (Box 12)
      - Daubigny, Charles, 1817-1878 (Box 12)
      - Daumier, Honore, 1808-1879 (Box 12–13)
      - David, J.L., 1748-1825 (Box 13)
      - Debucourt, Philibert, 1755-1832 (Box 13)
      - Degas, Edgar, 1834-1917 (Box 13)
      - Delacroix, Eugene, 1798-1863 (Box 13)
      - Delaune, Etienne, 1519-1583 (Box 13)
      - Derain, Andre (Box 13)
      - Descourts, Charles-Melchoir, 1753-1820 (Box 13)
      - Doliver (Box 13)
      - Dore, Gustave, 1832-1883 (Box 13)
      - Dorigny, Michel, 1616-1665 (Box 13)
      - Drevet, Pierre, 1663-1783 (Box 13)
      - Du Pres, Jean (Box 13)
      - Duvet, Jean, 1485-1561 (Box 14)
      - Edelinck, Ger. (Box 14)
      - Eisen, Charles, 1720-1778 (Box 14)
      - Fantin-La Tour, Henri, 1836-1904 (Box 14)
      - Forain, Jean Louis, 1852-1931 (Box 14)
      - Fragonard, J.H., 1732-1806 (Box 14)
      - Galliot, Bernard (Box 14)
      - Gauguin, Paul, 1843-1903 (Box 14)
      - Gerard, Francois Pascal Simon, 1770-1837 (Box 14)
      - Gericault, Theodore, 1791-1837 (Box 14)
      - Gillot, Claude, 1673-1722 (Box 14)
      - Gravelot, Hubert Francois, 1699-1773 (Box 14)
      - Greuze, J.B. (after) (Box 14)
      - Husz, M.L. (Box 14)
      - Ingres, J.A.D., 1780-1867 (Box 14)
      - Isabey, Eugene, 1804-1886 (Box 14)
      - Jacques, Charles (Box 14)
      - Janinet, Jean Francois, 1752-1814 (Box 14)
      - Johannot, Alfred (Box 14)
      - La jave, Jacque, 1687-1761 (Box 14)
      - Laurincin, Marie (Box 15)
      - Le Geay, Jean Laurent (Box 15)
      - Legros, Alphonse, 1830-1911 (Box 15)
      - Lennert, P.F (Box 15)
      - LePautre, Jean, 1617-1682 (Box 15)
      - Le Prince, Jean Baptiste., 1734-1781 (Box 15)
      - L'Ormb, Philibert de (Box 15)
      - Luce, Maximilien, 1858-1941 (Box 15)
      - Mailoll, Artiside (Box 15)
      - Malapeau, C.P. (Box 15)
      - Manet, Edouard, 1832-1883 (Box 15)
      - Matisse, Henri, 1869-1954 (Box 15)
      - Meissonier, J.M. (Box 15)
      - Mellan, Claude, 1598-1688 (Box 15)
      - Meryon, Charles, 1821-1868 (Box 15)
      - Millet, Jean Francois, 1814-1875 (Box 15)
      - Moreau, Jean-Michel. 1741-1814 (Box 16)
      - Morin, Jean (Box 16)
      - Nanteuil, Robert, 1623/30-1678 (Box 16)
        - Anne of Austria (Box 16)
        - Bernard De Foix De La Valette (Box 16)
        - Bossuet (Box 16)
        - Colbert, Jean-Baptiste (Box 16)
        - Frederick-Maurice De La Tour D'Auvergne (Box 16)
        - Duc D'Albert (Box 16)
        - Fouquet, Nicholas (Box 16)
        - Francois De Clermont Tonnerre (Box 16)
        - Hardouin de Perefixe (Box 16)
        - Hesselin, Louis (Box 16)
        - Loret, Jean (Box 16)
        - Louis XIV (Box 16)
        - Michel De Marolles (Box 16)
        - Cardinal Mazarin (Box 16)
        - Mole, Edouard (Box 16)
        - Mole, Francois (Box 16)
        - Pompone De Bellieure (Box 16)
        - Le Prince De Conde (Box 16)
        - Cardinal De Retz (Box 16)
        - Cardinal Richelieu (Box 16)
        - Denis Talon (Box 16)
        - Victor Le Bouthelier (Box 16)
      - Nicholas Le Rouge (Box 16)
      - Papillon, Jean, 1639-1710 (Box 16)
      - Perrier, Francois, 1590-1650 (Box 16)
      - Picart, Bernard, 1673-1733 (Box 16)
      - Pillement, Jean (Box 16)
      - Pissarro, Camille, 1830-1903 (Box 17)
      - Prevost, Alexander, ac.1850-1886 (Box 17)
      - Raffet, Auguste, 1804-1860 (Box 17)
      - Redon, Odilon, 1840-1916 (Box 17)
      - Renoir, Pierre A., 1841-1919 (Box 17)
      - Reverdy, Georges, ac.1531-1560 (Box 17)
      - Riviere, Henri (Box 17)
      - Rodin, Auguste (Box 17)
      - Roualt, Georges, 1871-1958 (Box 17)
      - Rousseau, Theodore (Box 17)
      - Saint-Aubin, brothers (Box 17)
      - Salmon, Gabriel (Box 17)
      - Soulages, Pierre, 1919- (Box 17)
      - Steinlen, Alexandre Theophile 1859-1923 (Box 17)
      - Stella, Jacques, 1595-1657 (Box 17)
      - Tardieu, N.H. (Box 17)
      - Tory, Geoffrey (Box 17)
      - Toulouse-Lautrec, Henri, 1864-1901 (Box 17)
      - Vignon, Claude, 1593-1670 (Box 17)
      - Vuillard, Jean Eduardo, 1868-1940 (Box 17)
      - Watteau, Jean-A (after), 1684-1721 (Box 18)
  - Germany (Box 18)
    - 15th Century (Box 18)
      - Dotted Prints (Box 18)
      - Nuremberg Chronicle, 1943 (Box 18)
      - Master B.M., ac.1480-1500 (Box 19)
      - Master of the Banderolles (Box 19)
      - Master E.S., ac.1440-1468 (Box 19)
      - Master F.V.B (Box 19)
      - Master of the Hausbuch (Box 19)
      - Master I A M of Zwolle (Box 19)
      - Master M.Z. (Box 19)
        Xx Zasinger
      - Master P.M. (Box 19)
      - Master of the Playing Cards (Box 19)
      - Master of the Weibermacht (Box 19)
      - Master of 1446 (Box 19)
    - 16th Century (Box 19)
      - Master A.G. (Box 19)
      - Master I.G. (Box 19)
      - Master H.L (Box 19)
    - 18th Century (Box 19)
      - Winkelmann, J.J. (Box 19)
    - 19th Century (Box 19)
    - Unknown Artists (Box 19)
    - Known Artists (Box 19)
      - Aldegrever, H., 1502-1558 (Box 19)
      - Altdorfer, A.lbrecht, c.1480-1538 (Box 19–20)
      - Amman, Jost, 1539-1591 (Box 20)
      - Baldung-Grien, Hans, 1480-1545 (Box 20)
      - Beham, Barthel, 1502-1540 (Box 20)
      - Beham, Hans Sebald (Box 20)
      - Burgkmair, Hans, 1473-1531 (Box 20)
      - Campendonk, H., 1889-1921 (Box 20)
      - Chardella, Simon Nicolai (Box 20)
      - Cranach, Lucas (elder), 1472-1553 (Box 21)
      - Cranach, Lucas (younger), 1515-1586 (Box 21)
      - Dieterlin, Wendel, c.1550-1599 (Box 21)
      - Durer, Albrecht, 1471-1528 (Box 21)
        - Allegory (Box 21)
          - Melancholia (Box 21)
          - Knigh, Death and the Devil (Box 21)
          - Nemesis (The Great Fortune) (Box 21)
        - Animals (Box 21)
        - Book Illustration (Box 21)
        - Designs (Box 21)
          - Triumphal Arch (Box 21)
        - Mythological (Box 21)
        - Portraits (Box 22)
        - Religions (Box 22)
          - Various Titles (Box 22)
          - Adam & Eve (Box 22)
          - Apocalypse (Box 22)
          - Life of the Virgin (Box 22)
          - Engraved Passion (Box 22)
          - Large Passion (Box 22)
          - Little Passion (Box 22)
          - Saints (Box 22)
            - S. Jerome (Box 22)
          - Virgin & Holy Families (Box 22)
          - Secular (Box 23)
          - Theory & Measurement (Box 23)
      - Ernst, Max, 1891-1976 (Box 23)
      - Flotner, Peter, 1491-1546 (Box 23)
      - Fust and Schoeffer, 15th century (Box 23)
      - Grosz, George, 1893-1959 (Box 23)
      - Gutenberg, Mainz (Box 23)
      - Han, Ulrich (Box 23)
      - Hartung, Hans, 1904- (Box 23)
      - Harloerth, Willi Klingsport Press (Box 23)
      - Heckel, Erich, 1883-1949 (Box 23)
      - Hirschvogel, A., 1503-1553 (Box 23)
      - Holbein, Hans (younger), 1497-1543 (Box 23)
        - Dance of Death (Box 23)
      - Hollar, Wenzel, 1607-1677 (Box 23)
      - Hopfer, Daniel (elder), 1470-1536 (Box 23)
      - Hopfer, Daniel, fl. 1493-1536 (Box 23)
      - Hopfer, Jerome (Hieronymus), 1520-1550 (Box 24)
      - Hopfer, Lambert fl. 1520-1530 (Box 24)
      - Kirchner, Ernst Ludwig, 1880-1936 (Box 24)
      - Klein, J.A., 1792-1875 (Box 24)
      - Koberger, A. (Box 24)
      - Koch, Jodef Anton, 1768-1830 (Box 24)
      - Kolbe, Carl Wilhem, 1781-1853 (Box 24)
      - Kollwitz, Kathe, 1867-1945 (Box 24)
      - Lautensack, Hans, 1524-1561/6 (Box 24)
      - Leblon, Jakob C., 1667-1741 (Box 24)
      - Mair Von Landshut, N.A., ac.1492-1514 (Box 24)
      - Marc, Franz, 1880-1916 (Box 24)
      - Meckenem, Isrhael van, C.1445-1503 (Box 24)
      - Menzel, Adolph, 1815-1905 (Box 24)
      - Oliver, Fernand, 1785-1841 (Box 24)
      - Pencz, George, 1500-1550 (Box 25)
      - Rethel, Alfred, 1816-1859 (Box 25)
      - Richter, Ludwig Adrian, 1803-1884 (Box 25)
      - Rupert, von der Pfalz, Prince (Box 25)
      - Ryff, Walther (Box 25)
      - Schauffelin, Hans, c.1490-1539 (Box 25)
      - Schmidt, Georg Friedrich, 1712-1775 (Box 25)
      - Schoen, Erhard, 1491? -1542 (Box 25)
      - Schongauer, Martin, c.1430-1491 (Box 25)
      - Scgwitters, Kurt, 1887- (Box 25)
      - Stoss, Viet, 1438-1533 (Box 25)
      - Traut, Wolfgag, c.1486-1520 (Box 25)
      - Vogtherr, Heinrich (younger), 1513-1568 (Box 25)
      - Wechtlin, Hans, c.1480-1520 (Box 25)
      - Weiditz, Hans II, ac.1516-1536 (Box 25)
      - Werdt, Abraham von (Box 25)
      - Willie, Johann Georg (Box 25)
      - Wolgemut, Michael (Box 25)
      - Zainer, Johann (Box 25)
      - Zasinger, Matthaus, ac.1500 (Box 25)
  - Holland (Box 25)
    - Anthonisz, Cornelius (Box 25)
    - Bercham, Nicolaes (Box 25)
    - Bloemart, Abraham, 1564-1651 (Box 26)
    - Blootering, Abraham, 1640-1690 (Box 26)
    - Bol, Ferdinand, 1616-c.1580 (Box 26)
    - Gheyn, Jacob van, 1565-1629 (Box 26)
    - Goltzius, Hendrik, 1558-1617 (Box 26)
    - Goudt, Hendrick, 1578-1630 (Box 26)
    - Heemskerck, Martin, 1498-1574 (Box 26)
    - Hooghe, Roman de, 1645-1708 (Box 26)
    - Lievens, Jan 1607-1674 (Box 26)
    - Lucas Von Leyden, 1494-1533 (Box 26)
    - Mathan, Jacob, 1571-1631 (Box 26)
    - Ostade, Simon von de, c. 1595-1647 (Box 26)
    - Potter, Paul, 1625-1654 (Box 26)
    - Rembrandt Van Rijin, 1606-1669 [Boxes 26-29] (Box 26)
      - Animals (Box 26)
      - Genre Scenes (Box 27)
      - Figures & Figure Studies (Box 27)
      - Landscapes (Box 27)
        - Amsterdam (Box 27)
        - Goldweicher's Field (Box 27)
        - Landscape with Milkman (Box 27)
        - Landscape with Thatched Cottage & Ahay Barn (Box 27)
        - Landscape with Cottage and Large Tree (Box 27)
        - Landscape with Three Cabled Cottages (Box 27)
        - Six's Bridge (Box 27)
        - Three Trees (Box 27)
        - Windmill (Box 27)
      - Portraits (Box 27)
        - General (Box 27)
        - Clement De Jonghe (Box 28)
        - Dr. Ephraim Bueno (Box 28)
        - Faustus (Box 28)
        - Jewish Bride (Box 28)
        - Mother (Box 28)
        - Rembrandt & Saskia (Box 28)
        - Self Portraits (Box 28)
        - Three Heads of Women (Box 28)
      - Religious (Box 28)
        - Abraham & Hagar (Box 28)
        - Christ Preaching (Box 28)
        - Christ Presented to the People (Box 28)
        - Crucifixions (Box 28)
        - Descent from the Cross (Box 28)
        - Entombment (Box 28)
        - Healing the Sick (100 Guilder) (Box 28)
        - Presentation in Temple (Box 28)
        - Prodigal Son (Box 28)
        - Raising of Lazarus (Box 29)
        - S. Jerome in an Italian Landscape (Box 29)
        - S. Jerome beside a Tree stump (Box 29)
        - The Three Crosses (Box 29)
        - Tobit (Box 29)
    - Ruysdael, Jacob van, c.1630-1682 (Box 29)
    - Sauery, Solomon, 1594-1665 (Box 29)
    - Seghers, Hercules, c.1590-c.1640 (Box 29)
    - Toorop, Jan, 1858-1928 (Box 29)
    - Valckert, Werner van der, 1580-1655 (Box 29)
    - Van Gogh, Vincent, 1853-1890 (Box 29)
    - Velde, Esias van de, 1951-1630 (Box 29)
    - Velde, Jan Van de, 1593-1641 (Box 29)
    - Velde, Jan Van de (III) (Box 29)
    - Vellert, Dirick Jocabus, 1511-44 (Box 29)
    - Visscher, Cornelius, 1629?-1658? (Box 30)
    - Visscher, C.I. (Box 30)
    - Vastermans, Lucas (Box 30)
    - Vries, Hans Vredeman de (Jan), 1526-1606 (Box 30)
    - Waterloo. Anthonie, c.1610-1690 (Box 30)
    - Wingendorp, G. (Box 30)
    - Zeeman, Rener Nooms, 1623-1673 (Box 30)
  - Italy (Box 30)
    - 13th Century (Box 30)
      - Woodcuts (Box 30)
    - 15th Century (Box 30)
      - Woodcuts (Box 30)
      - Engraving (Box 30)
      - Nielli (Box 30)
      - Prophets & Sibyls (Box 30)
      - Otto Prints (Box 30)
      - Tarocchi Cards (Box 30)
      - Triumphs of Petrarch (Box 31)
      - Master of the Larger Vienna Passion (Box 31)
      - Master of the Sforza Book of Hours (Box 31)
    - 16th Century (Box 31)
      - Various Titles (Box 31)
      - Woodcuts (Box 31)
      - Etchings (Box 31)
      - Engravings (Box 31)
      - Master I.B. with Bird (Box 31)
    - 17th Century (Box 31)
      - Various Titles (Box 31)
      - Cesare Ripa, Iconologia (Box 31)
    - 18th Century (Box 31)
      - Delle Antichita D'Ercolano Neples, 1755-1815 (Box 31)
    - Artists (Box 31)
      - Andreani, Andres, c.1546-1623 (Box 31)
      - Antonio da Trento (Box 31)
      - Arcimboldo, Giuseppe (Box 31)
      - Baldini, Boccio (Box 32)
      - Barbari, Jacopi di, 1450-1516 (Box 32)
      - Bartolozzi, Francesco, 1727-1815 (Box 32)
      - Bergomensis, Petrus (Box 32)
      - Bibiena (Box 32)
      - Boldrini, Nicolo (Box 32)
      - Botticelli (after) (Box 32)
      - Bramante (Box 32)
      - Brescia, Giov. Ant. Da fl.1500-1516 (Box 32)
      - Cambiaso, Luca (Box 32)
      - Campagnola, Domenico, 1482-1562 (Box 32)
      - Campagnola, Giulio, 1482-1515 (Box 32)
      - Campo, Antonio (Box 32)
      - Canal, Antonio, 1697-1768 (Box 32)
        X Canaletto
      - Cantagallina, Remigio, c.1585-1656 (Box 32)
      - Carpi, Ugo da, c.1479-1532 (Box 32)
      - Carracci, Annibale, 1560-1609 (Box 32)
      - Carraci, Agostino, 1557-1602 (Box 32)
      - Castiglione, Giovanni Benedetto., 1616-1670 (Box 32)
      - Cesarini (Box 32)
      - Dente, Marco (Box 32)
      - Fantuzzi, Antonio, c.1508-1550 (Box 32)
      - Feretti, D. (Box 32)
      - Johannes ex Verona (Box 33)
      - Lasinio, Carlo, 1757-1839 (Box 33)
      - Lauri, Giacomo, ac.1585-1612 (Box 33)
      - Leonardo da Vinci, School of (Box 33)
      - Leoni, Octavius M., 1578-1630 (Box 33)
      - Mantegna, Andrea, 1431-1506 (Box 33)
      - Messin, Bartolommeo Olives de (Box 33)
      - Montagna, Benedetto, 1481-1558 (Box 33)
      - Nicoletto da Modena, 1450-1540 (Box 33)
      - Parmigianino, 1503-1540 (Box 33)
      - Piranesi, G.B., 1720-1778 (Box 33)
        - Antichita Romane (Box 33)
        - Vedute di Roma (Box 33–34)
      - Pollaiulo, Antonio, 1433-1498 (Box 34)
      - Pomorancio, Niccolo (Box 34)
      - Raibolini, Francesco (Box 34)
      - Raimondi, Marcantonio., 1480-1527 (Box 34)
      - Raphael Sanzio, 1483-1520 (Box 34)
      - Reni, Guido, 1575-1642 (Box 34)
      - Robetta, Christoforo (Box 34)
      - Rosa, Salvador, 1615-1673 (Box 34)
      - Rosselli, Francesco, 1448-1513 (Box 34)
      - Rosso Fiorentino, 1494-1540 (Box 34)
        X Rosso Fiorentino (Giovanni) or Il Rosso
      - Stoa, J. F.O. (Box 34)
      - Tempesta, Antonio, 1555-1630 (Box 34)
      - Testa, Pietro, 1611-1650 (Box 34)
      - Tiepolo, Dominico (Box 34)
      - Tiepolo, Giovanni, 1696-1770 (Box 34)
      - Titian, 1477-1576 (Box 34)
      - Vico, Enea, 1520-1563/7 (Box 34)
      - Villamena, Francesco, 1566-1624 (Box 34)
      - Zoan, Andrea, ca.1475-1515 (Box 34)
      - Zucchi, Giuseppe, 1711-1767 (Box 35)
  - Norway (Box 35)
    - Munch, Edvard, 1863-1944 (Box 35)
  - Russia (Box 35)
    - Chagall, Marc, 1887-1985 (Box 35)
    - Kandinsky, Wassily, 1866-1944 (Box 35)
    - Lissitzky, El, 1890-1941 (Box 35)
    - Poliakoff, Serge, 1906- (Box 35)
    - Starronoscov, Peter N. Active 1934 (Box 35)
    - Yakunchikova (Box 35)
  - Spain (Box 35)
    - Artists Unknown (Box 35)
    - Arteaga Y. Alfaro, Mathias, 1630-1763 (Box 35)
    - Goya, Francisco, 1746-1828 (Box 35)
      - Various Titles (Box 35)
      - Caprichos (Box 35–36)
      - The Disasters of War (Box 36)
      - Proverbs (Box 36)
      - Tauromaquia (Box 36)
    - Miro, Joan (Box 36)
    - Morante (Box 36)
    - Palomino, Antonio, 1653-1726 (Box 36)
    - Picasso, Pablo, 1881-1973 (Box 36–37)
    - Ribera, Jusepe, 1588-1652 (Box 37)
    - Valdes Leal, Juan de, 1622-1690 (Box 37)
    - Vega, Pedro de (Box 37)
  - Sweden (Box 37)